
const questionsData = {
  parts: [
    [
      { question: "7 − 7 × 7 ÷ 7 + 7 = ?", options: ["6", "7", "8", "14"], answer: "7" },
      { "question": "What is the average of 1, 5, 7, 8 and 9?", "options": ["5", "7", "6", "8"], "answer": "6" },
      { "question": "Find the next number in the sequence: 1, 11, 21, 1211, 111221, ?", "options": ["13112221", "211321", "1113213211", "312211"], "answer": "312211" },
      { "question": "How many two-digit numbers including the digit 3 can be formed from 3, 5, 2, 8, 7, 6?", "options": ["11", "10", "12", "9"], "answer": "11" },
      { "question": "Find the fourth proportion to the numbers 20, 32 and 36.", "options": ["54.2", "58.2", "57.6", "56.4"], "answer": "57.6" },
      { "question": "What is the remainder when 4 power(999) is divided by 7?", "options": ["3", "5", "2", "1"], "answer": "1" },
      { "question": "What is the remainder when 17⁵⁰ is divided by 23?", "options": ["9", "12", "1", "3"], "answer": "9" },
      { "question": "What is the remainder when 999⁹⁹ is divided by 13?", "options": ["1", "7", "9", "3"], "answer": "3" },
      { "question": "A train travels at a constant speed of 60 km/h. A man is walking along the train track at 6 km/h. When the train approaches from behind, it takes 10 seconds to overtake him completely. If the man turns around and walks toward the train at the same speed (6 km/h), how long will the train take to pass him completely?", "options": ["12 seconds", "9 seconds", "7 seconds", "8 seconds"], "answer": "8 seconds" },
      { "question": "A farmer travelled a distance of 70 km in 10 hours. He travelled partly on foot at 5 km/h and partly on bicycle at 10 km/h. The distance travelled on foot is:", "options": ["20 km", "25 km", "30 km", "35 km"], "answer": "30 km" },
      { "question": "A bus departs from City A and travels towards City B at a constant speed of 70 km/h. Due to traffic, it takes exactly 36 minutes for the bus to cover a certain portion of its journey before making a scheduled halt at a rest stop.", "options": ["40 km", "45 km", "42 km", "48 km"], "answer": "42 km" },
      { "question": "Which two numbers from amongst the given options should be interchanged to make the given equation correct? 140 ÷ 7 + 112 ÷ (4 × 5 − 2 × 5) = 30", "options": ["Interchange 140 and 112", "Interchange 140 and 30", "Interchange 112 and 4", "Interchange 5 and 7"], "answer": "Interchange 140 and 112" },
      { "question": "Which numbers should be interchanged to make the given equation correct? 52 ÷ 13 + 6 − 25 × 2 = 17", "options": ["2 and 25", "13 and 25", "6 and 25", "52 and 25"], "answer": "6 and 25" },
      { "question": "Select the correct combination of mathematical signs to sequentially replace the * signs and balance the given equation. 33 * 4 * 15 * 3 * 61 = 188", "options": ["+ × − ÷", "× − ÷ +", "÷ + × −", "− × + ÷"], "answer": "× − ÷ +" },
      { "question": "You are participating in a 10-kilometer race. You manage to overtake the person who is currently in 2nd place. There are also 5 other runners behind you, and your shoelace comes untied right as you pass the 7-kilometer mark. What position are you in now?", "options": ["3rd place", "1st place", "2nd place", "4th place"], "answer": "2nd place" },
      { "question": "Imagine you decide to invest in Tesla shares. In the first quarter, due to strong sales figures and positive market sentiment, the value of your Tesla shares increased by 20%. However, in the following quarter, market volatility and increased competition caused the value of your shares to drop by 20% from their new, higher value. Compared to your initial investment, what is the net percentage change in the value of your Tesla shares after these two quarters?", "options": ["A 4% increase", "A 4% decrease", "A 96% increase", "A 96% decrease"], "answer": "A 4% decrease" },
      { "question": "A man buys two watches for ₹2000. He sells one at a gain of 20% and the other at a loss of 10%. If on the whole he neither gains nor loses, find the cost price of each watch.", "options": ["₹777.77 & ₹1300.33", "₹888.87 & ₹1122.13", "₹666.67 & ₹1333.33", "₹999.99 & ₹1111.11"], "answer": "₹666.67 & ₹1333.33" },
      { "question": "A is twice as efficient as B. Together, they can complete a piece of work in 14 days. In how many days can A alone complete the same work?", "options": ["4 week", "2 weeks", "1 weeks", "3 weeks"], "answer": "3 weeks" },
      { "question": "The ratio of boys to girls in a class is 2:5. If there are 14 more girls than boys, how many students are there in total?", "options": ["42", "45", "49", "56"], "answer": "49" },
      { "question": "The ratio of the ages of A and B is 4:3. After 7 years, the ratio becomes 5:4. What is A's present age?", "options": ["24 years", "28 years", "32 years", "30 years"], "answer": "28 years" },
      { "question": "The weight of Anjali is 60 kg. After three months, her weight increased by 20% and in the next three months, it increased by 25%. What will be the weight (in kg) of Anjali after six months?", "options": ["90 kg", "92 kg", "95 kg", "86 kg"], "answer": "90 kg" },
      { "question": "The compound interest on ₹50,000 at the rate of 7% per annum compounded annually, for a certain period of time, is ₹7,245. Find the time period (in years).", "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"], "answer": "2" },
      { "question": "Ramesh saves 28% of his salary, while Naresh saves 32%. If both get the same salary and Naresh saves Rs.1,736, what is the expenditure of Ramesh?", "options": ["Rs. 3906", "Rs. 4102", "Rs. 3840", "Rs. 4006"], "answer": "Rs. 3906" },
      { "question": "Ajay offers his customers a discount of 20% on an overcoat and he still makes a profit of 28%. What is the actual cost of the overcoat marked at ₹1,800?", "options": ["₹1,150", "₹1,125", "₹1,140", "₹1,175"], "answer": "₹1,125" },
      { "question": "A is the average of 10 given numbers. B is the average after 2 of the numbers were replaced by 3 other different numbers. The average of the removed numbers is 48 and the average of the newly included numbers is 56. If A + B = 438, then the value of A − B is:", "options": ["12", "16", "13", "14"], "answer": "14" },
      { "question": "Select the option that is related to the fourth term in the same way as the first term is related to the second term and the fifth term is related to the sixth term 8 : 508 :: ? : 2193 :: 2 : 4", "options": ["13", "14", "16", "15"], "answer": "13" },
      { "question": "A seven-digit number 5702718 is divisible by 147. If we rearrange the digits of the number in descending order and subtract 4 more than three times of 17 from the new number which is formed, then the resultant number will be divisible by:", "options": ["3", "5", "7", "10"], "answer": "5" },
      { "question": "A five-digit number 73128 is divisible by 147. If all the digits are arranged in descending order and from this number you subtract 4 more than three times of 17, then the resultant number will be divisible by:", "options": ["7", "9", "12", "15"], "answer": "7" },
      { "question": "A vessel contains a mixture of milk and water in the ratio 7:5. If 12 liters of this mixture is replaced with pure milk, the new ratio becomes 9:5. Find the total capacity of the vessel.", "options": ["48 liters", "60 liters", "72 liters", "84 liters"], "answer": "72 liters" },
      { "question": "Three vessels contain mixtures of milk and water in the following ratios: First: 2:1 Second: 3:2 Third: 5:3 If 20 liters from the first, 30 liters from the second, and x liters from the third are mixed together, the resulting mixture has milk to water in the ratio 4:3. Find the value of x.", "options": ["32 liters", "28 liters", "30 liters", "34 liters"], "answer": "32 liters" }
    ],
    [
      { "question": "START → TSBPS : SOTI → ?", "options": ["TNUI", "TNUH", "SNUI", "TNSH"], "answer": "TNUH" },
      { "question": "Look at this series: 2, 1, (1/2), (1/4), … What number should come next?", "options": ["(1/3)", "(1/8)", "(2/8)", "(1/16)"], "answer": "(1/8)" },
      { "question": "Parts : Strap :: Wolf : ?", "options": ["Flow", "Animal", "Wood", "Fox"], "answer": "Flow" },
      { "question": "In a certain code language: 412 = sweet cold coffee, 142 = very sweet coffee, 312 = hot cold coffee. Which of the following digits represents 'cold'?", "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"], "answer": "1" },
      { "question": "17, 21, 28, 38, 51, 67, ?", "options": ["85", "86", "88", "90"], "answer": "86" },
      { "question": "Eight people — A, B, C, D, E, F, G, and H — are sitting around a circular table. Some are facing the center, and some are facing outside.A sits second to the left of G.B sits third to the right of A.D sits opposite B and faces the center.E is an immediate neighbor of D and G.C sits exactly between F and H.F faces the center.Both the immediate neighbors of G face outside.who is sitting third to the right of C?", "options": ["A", "F", "G", "H"], "answer": "G" },
      { "question": "‘P @ Q’ means ‘P is the mother of Q’. ‘P & Q’ means ‘P is the brother of Q’. ‘P # Q’ means ‘P is the sister of Q’  If ‘A @ B # C & D @ E # F’, then how is A related to E?", "options": ["Sister", "Mother’s brother", "Daughter", "Mother’s mother"], "answer": "Mother’s mother" },
      { "question": "‘A # B’ means ‘A is the brother of B’. ‘A @ B’ means ‘A is the daughter of B’. ‘A & B’ means ‘A is the husband of B’. ‘A % B’ means ‘A is the wife of B’ If W % D # G @ B & M @ I, then how is D related to M?", "options": ["Grandson", "Father’s father", "Father", "Son"], "answer": "Son" },
      { "question": "Only a few sky is blue. No blue are azure. Some heaven are azure. Conclusions: I. All heaven can never be blue. II. All sky are azure is a possibility.", "options": ["Only I follows", "Both I and II follow", "Only II follows", "Either I or II follows", "None follows"], "answer": "Only I follows" },
      { "question": "In a certain code language, ‘FRANK’ is written as ‘121811422’ and ‘CRIED’ is written as ‘618958’. How will ‘GREAT’ be written in that language?", "options": ["13185140", "14185140", "14195140", "14184140"], "answer": "14185140" },
      { "question": "Pointing towards a woman in the photograph, Rahul said, “She is the mother of the only daughter of my son-in-law, Harish.” How is she related to Rahul?", "options": ["Wife", "Daughter", "Sister", "Sister-in-law"], "answer": "Daughter" },
      { "question": "A direction pole turned. East started showing South. One traveler went to the wrong direction thinking it to be West. In what direction was he actually travelling?", "options": ["South", "East", "West", "North"], "answer": "North" },
      { "question": "Four people are suspected of stealing a gold necklace. Each makes two statements. One of their statements is true, and one is false. Who is the thief?  Aarav says: It was Aarav. It wasn’t Kabir.Kabir says: It was Siya. It wasn’t Aarav.Rohan says: It was Kabir. It wasn’t Siya.Siya says: It was Rohan. It was Aarav.", "options": ["Siya", "Rohan", "Aarav", "Kabir"], "answer": "Rohan" },
      { "question": "Choose the correct alternative: ab __ aa __ bbb __ aaa __ bbba", "options": ["abab", "abba", "aaab", "baab"], "answer": "baab" },
      { "question": "1, 2, 2, 4, 3, 8, 7, 10, ?", "options": ["11", "13", "9", "8"], "answer": "11" },
      { "question": " If 3x + 2y = 12 and 5x − y = 13, what is the value of x + y?", "options": ["3", "5", "7", "9"], "answer": "5" },
      { "question": "A trader marked his goods 40% above the cost price and allows a discount of 10%. What is his profit percentage?","options": ["26%", "30%", "28%", "25%"],"answer": "26%" },
      { "question": "Synonym of 'loathe:'", "options": ["argue", "hate", "discover", "reveal"], "answer": "hate" },
      { "question": "Synonym of the 'buffet:'", "options": ["protect", "barricade", "armoire", "strike"], "answer": "strike" },
      { "question": "I _________ the idea of my latest project while visiting Goa on a vacation.", "options": ["concieved", "conceived", "perceived", "deceived"], "answer": "conceived" },
      { "question": "It was an excellent social evening with people from all _______ of life getting a chance to let their hair _______.", "options": ["areas, drop", "realms, flow", "arena, undone", "walks, down"], "answer": "walks, down" },
      { "question": "Which of the following demonstrates correct subject-verb agreement?", "options": ["The team are going to the match tomorrow.", "Each of the boys have their own opinion.", "The flock of birds is flying south for the winter.", "The group of students is studying for their exams."], "answer": "The flock of birds is flying south for the winter." },
      { "question": "What is the next number in the series: 7, 26, 63, 124, ?", "options": ["215", "216", "217", "218"],"answer": "215" },
      { "question": "Find the part of the sentence that contains an error: -- If I was you, I would reconsider the decision carefully.", "options": ["was you", "were you", "am you", "no correction required"], "answer": "were you" },
      {"question": "In how many ways can the letters of the word 'EXAMINATION' be arranged so that all vowels come together?",    "options": ["302400", "288000", "216000", "120000"],"answer": "302400"},
      { "question": "A can do a piece of work in 10 days, B in 15 days. A and B work together for 5 days, then B leaves. How many more days will A take to finish the work?","options": ["2", "3", "4", "5"],    "answer": "4"},
      { "question": "Many believe that technology is shrinking the world, bringing people closer through digital communication. However, some sociologists argue that while online interactions increase, face-to-face relationships suffer. Digital connections may offer convenience but lack depth and emotional nuance that real-world interactions provide.", "options": ["Technology has made communication completely emotionless.", "Digital communication is better than face-to-face interaction", "Technology connects people but may weaken real-world relationships.", "Sociologists dislike digital communication.."], "answer": "Technology connects people but may weaken real-world relationships." },
      { "question": "The Amazon rainforest produces 20% of the world’s oxygen and is home to countless species. Despite its importance, deforestation due to logging and agriculture continues at an alarming rate. Environmentalists warn that if these activities aren't controlled, the global climate could face irreversible damage.", "options": ["Indifferent", "Cautionary", "Optimistic", "Humorous"], "answer": "Cautionary" },
      { "question": "In ancient times, libraries were accessible only to scholars and royalty. Books were handwritten, making them rare and valuable. The invention of the printing press changed this, making books available to the masses and laying the foundation for public education systems worldwide. Which of the following best summarizes the paragraph?", "options": ["Public education is more important than libraries", "The printing press democratized access to books and knowledge.", "Ancient libraries were better than modern", "Printing presses are rarely used today"], "answer": "The printing press democratized access to books and knowledge" },
      { "question": "In recent years, remote work has gained popularity, offering employees flexibility and eliminating commuting time. However, it has also led to challenges such as blurred boundaries between personal and professional life, reduced team collaboration, and potential feelings of isolation. Companies are now exploring hybrid models to balance both benefits and drawbacks.","options":[" Remote work eliminates all problems related to office work", "Hybrid models attempt to combine flexibility with team collaboration", "Remote work is harmful and should be avoided.", "Companies want split time"], "answer": "Hybrid models attempt to combine flexibility with team collaboration." }
    ],
    [
      { "question": "What is the next number in the sequence? 1, 3, 5, 7, 9.", "options": ["10", "11", "12", "13"], "answer": "11" },
      { "question": "If 2 apples cost ₹10, how much would 5 apples cost?", "options": ["₹20", "₹25", "₹30", "₹35"], "answer": "₹25" },
      { "question": "Which two numbers should be interchanged to make the equation correct? 10 × 2 ÷ 5 = 1.", "options": ["10 and 2", "2 and 5", "10 and 5", "2 and 1"], "answer": "10 and 5" },
      { "question": "A man travels 120 km in 3 hours. What is his average speed?", "options": ["30 km/h", "40 km/h", "50 km/h", "60 km/h"], "answer": "40 km/h" },
      { "question": "A train 120 meters long passes a pole in 12 seconds. What is its speed?", "options": ["10 m/s", "12 m/s", "14 m/s", "16 m/s"], "answer": "10 m/s" },
      { "question": "Simplify: 45% of 200 + 30% of 500 = ?", "options": ["180", "220", "240", "260"], "answer": "240" },
      { "question": "If a book costs 10% less than its marked price of ₹500, what is its selling price?", "options": ["₹400", "₹450", "₹480", "₹500"], "answer": "₹450" },
      { "question": "Find the missing number: 4, 9, 16, 25, ___.", "options": ["30", "36", "40", "49"], "answer": "36" },
      { "question": "A bag contains 6 red balls, 4 green balls, and 5 blue balls. What is the probability of drawing a red ball?", "options": ["6/15", "4/15", "2/5", "6/11"], "answer": "6/15" },
      { "question": "If x = 5, what is the value of 2x^2 - 3x + 9?", "options": ["39", "41", "44", "46"], "answer": "44" },
      { "question": "Renewable energy sources such as solar and wind power are becoming more popular as the world seeks sustainable solutions. However, storage and reliability remain challenges. What is the main focus?", "options": ["Only wind power is reliable.", "Renewable energy is both promising and challenging.", "Solar energy is enough for the world.", "Fossil fuels are not needed."], "answer": "Renewable energy is both promising and challenging." },
      { "question": "In the same passage, which of these is NOT mentioned?", "options": ["Storage challenges", "Cost reduction", "Wind power", "Sustainable solutions"], "answer": "Cost reduction" },
      { "question": "Regular exercise helps improve mental health by reducing stress and anxiety. It also contributes to physical health by maintaining weight and strengthening muscles. What is NOT a benefit mentioned?", "options": ["Improving skin tone", "Reducing stress", "Maintaining weight", "Strengthening muscles"], "answer": "Improving skin tone" },
      { "question": "The internet has revolutionized communication, allowing instant messaging and global collaboration. However, issues like misinformation persist. What is the downside mentioned?", "options": ["Global collaboration", "Instant messaging", "Misinformation", "Faster emails"], "answer": "Misinformation" },
      { "question": "Many animals migrate during certain seasons for food, breeding, or better climate. Birds and whales are common examples. Which is true?", "options": ["Only whales migrate.", "Migration happens randomly.", "Animals migrate for several reasons.", "Birds do not migrate."], "answer": "Animals migrate for several reasons." },
      { "question": "Match:\nBenevolent - A) Kind,  \nHostile - B) Angry\n,   Jubilant - C) Happy", "options": ["1-A, 2-B, 3-C", "1-B, 2-A, 3-C", "1-C, 2-B, 3-A", "1-A, 2-C, 3-B"], "answer": "1-A, 2-B, 3-C" },
      { "question": "Complete the series: A, C, E, G, ___.", "options": ["H", "I", "J", "K"], "answer": "I" },
      { "question": "If all dogs are animals, and all animals need water, which is true?", "options": ["Some dogs don't need water.", "All animals are dogs.", "All dogs need water.", "Only dogs need water."], "answer": "All dogs need water." },
      { "question": "Find the odd one out.", "options": ["Apple", "Banana", "Carrot", "Grape"], "answer": "Carrot" },
      { "question": "If in a code, CAT = 3120 (C=3, A=1, T=20), what does DOG equal?", "options": ["4157", "4159", "5149", "4149"], "answer": "4157" },
      { "question": "You are given a task deadline. What would you most likely do?", "options": ["Start early and plan.", "Wait until the last moment.", "Ignore it.", "Ask someone else to do it."], "answer": "Start early and plan." },
      { "question": "You notice a teammate struggling silently. How do you respond?", "options": ["Offer help.", "Ignore.", "Wait for them to ask.", "Criticize."], "answer": "Offer help." },
      { "question": "When under stress, what best describes you?", "options": ["Calm and focused.", "Panicked.", "Angry.", "Quit the task."], "answer": "Calm and focused." },
      { "question": "You are offered two job roles: one offers stability and predictable growth, another offers high risk but potentially high rewards. What do you prioritize?", "options": ["Stability and predictability.", "High risk and potential for high rewards.", "A mix of both if possible.", "Ask for more details before deciding."], "answer": "Stability and predictability." },
      { "question": "In a team, you prefer to:", "options": ["Lead.", "Follow.", "Stay neutral.", "Avoid teamwork."], "answer": "Lead." },
      { "question": "You fail in your first attempt. What do you do?", "options": ["Try again.", "Give up.", "Blame others.", "Ignore it."], "answer": "Try again." },
      { "question": "If a rule seems unfair, how do you handle it?", "options": ["Discuss calmly.", "Break it immediately.", "Ignore it.", "Complain to friends."], "answer": "Discuss calmly." },
      { "question": "During a group discussion, someone interrupts you. What do you do?", "options": ["Stay silent.", "Wait and speak later.", "Interrupt back.", "Leave the discussion."], "answer": "Wait and speak later." },
      {  "question": "A cube has a side length of 4 cm. If one face is painted and then the cube is cut into 1 cm³ cubes, how many small cubes have exactly one face painted?","options": ["16", "24", "36", "48"],    "answer": "24"},
      { "question": "Solve for x: 2x + 10 = 20", "options": ["3", "5", "8", "10"], "answer": "5" }
    ]
  ]
}
